VANESSA MITELMAN

Front End Developer

vanessamitelman@gmail.com | 0544741589 | Petah Tikva

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Vast experience developing websites using JavaScript technologies, catering to industry-standard methodologies and techniques with exposure to various platforms and software systems. Excellent analytical, high level and low-level design and problem-solving skills. Spectacular interpersonal skills with proficiency in oral and written communication abilities. Great time management and problem solving capabilities. Extensive experience in developing, enhancing and maintaining web applications. Skillful at developing multiple interfaces by reusing modules using MVC architecture.

Research-oriented, motivated, proactive, self-starter with strong technical, analytical and interpersonal skills. Good communication, interpersonal skills and problem-solving skills.

8+ years experience as a Front end developer.

8+ years of experience with CSS/SAAS (Preprocessors), Bootstrap and HTML.

Knowledge and practical experience with Javascript/JQuery.

Experience with ReactJS framework and knowledge in Redux and Webpack.

Knowledge and understanding of React Hooks, Styled Components, Global Themes, etc.

Experience with developing unit-tests.

Understand requirements and implement new features based on design and specifications provided.

Understanding of Front End component-based architecture.

Able to quickly learn and apply new technologies.

Able to work both independently with minimal direction and also to closely collaborate with fellow developers.

Working experience with GIT.

Languages:

English-Mother tongue Hebrew - fluent.

EDUCATION

BA in Statistics, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem

Oct 1995 - Jul 1998

I specialized in Biostatistics.

A degree in statistics equips me with strong data analysis, and great learning skills.

Computers, Ort Yad Leibovich High School, Netanya

Nov 1988 - Nov 1991

I learned technology basics and coding.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Web Developer, Menora Mivtachim Insurance LTD, Ramat Gan

Jun 2017 - Mar 2020

Experience with ReactJS framework and knowledge in Redux and Webpack

Vast experience working with React styled components.

Deep knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, SCSS and Bootstrap.

Experience with developing unit-tests.

Experience with Agile.

Deliver engaging user-experience through optimization of images, code and cross-browser compatibility, increasing Time on Page for multiple company websites and portals.

Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement. Designed dynamic, browser compatible and accessibility compliant web pages using HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, and Javascript (REACT). Built single page applications (SPA), responsive web design, UI using HTML5 grid layouts, Bootstrap, CSS3 media queries. Ensure efficient web

development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues.

Frontend Developer, eWave, Raanana

Sep 2015 - Jun 2017

Website Development using HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery.

Experience with jQueryUI widgets.

Experience and emphasis writing clear, clean and easily maintainable code..

Experience with mobile and implementing responsive designs

Worked on multiple projects across other UI technologies - Web / Html5.

Prioritized to meet deadlines in a fast-paced environment.

Web Developer, Freelance, Petach Tikva

Mar 2011 - Jun 2015

Website assessment, characterization and design

Deliver responsible, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant web pages.

Produce stunning visual elements for web applications.

Translate UI design wireframes into code.

Produce high quality, reusable markup using HTML5 and CSS3.

Design front end with jQuery.

Web Marketing Developer, SafeNet, Petach Tikva

Mar 2005 - Mar 2011

Managed CMS projects (Ektron)

Web developer: HTML, JavaScript, ASP

Web designer: CSS

Technical Release and QA Manager, Bug-Life Ltd. (Animation Software)

Mar 2000 - Mar 2002

QA team management.

Designed QA work processes

In-house training

Technical Support

QA Manager, Demantra (ERP - Demand Planning)

Mar 1998 - Mar 2000

QA Management (2 teams).

Trained 1/2/3rd line support and technical consultants abroad

Managing and supervising projects abroad

Involved in Release Management

Providing Technical Support

SKILLS

HTML/CSS

Javascript

CSS Preprocessors (SASS,SCSS)

Content Management Systems

Git/Version Control

Frameworks and Libraries (ReactJS)

Responsive/Mobile Design

Cross-Browser Development

Testing/Debugging

Problem Solving